1200 Landing Ln., Moon Township, PA 15108 **Campus Address**

Alexander Cash

614-593-6899 | aecst155@mail.rmu.edu | www.linkedin.com/in/alexander-cash | https://github.com/alcash55/Resume-Repository

5253 Stallion Ct. Liberty Township, OH 45011 Permanent Address

Class of 2020

GPA: 3.10

Professional Summary

Current D1 student-athlete entering in my Senior year at Robert Morris University working towards an ABET accredited degree in Software Engineering. Focused on developing new business and engineering skills while excited and looking forward to utilizing my current knowledge and experience in the work force.

Education

Robert Morris University, Moon Township, Pennsylvania

Engineering Bachelor of Science: Concentration in Software Engineering

Minor: Mechatronics

· Dean's List Spring 2018

Skills

Soft Skills: Teamwork, Team Building, Communication, Leadership, Public Speaking, Time Management, Organization **Software Development Experience:** Visual Studio, Eclipse, Java, JavaFX, C++, Python

Software Experience: GitHub, Autodesk AutoCAD, Autodesk Inventor, SolidWorks, Autodesk Revit, NI Multisim, and Microsoft Office

Professional Experience

Travel Lacrosse Coach (Resolute and Low and Away)

Communicate and teach defensive strategies, assist with designing practice plans, communicate weekend travel itineraries, and manage in-game player substitutions.

Worked an average of 8-10 hours a week and travel across east coast states for tournaments.

Resolute Lacrosse

Columbus & Cincinnati, OH | May 2017-July 2018

Joined as a junior coach assigned to work with the top 2022 graduating class and promoted to head defensive coach for the 2021 graduating class the following summer.

Low and Away Lacrosse

Greater Pittsburgh Area | June 2019 - Present

Joined as a practice coach working with all age groups, promoted to join for summer tournaments for the top 2020 class.

Involvement & Service

Robert Morris University Men's D1 Lacrosse Team

Moon Township, PA | Aug. 2016-Present

- Dedicate 20+ hours a week practicing lacrosse, lifting, and analyzing game and practice film while balancing a full academic course load
- Developed teamwork, and leadership skills while participating in team building activities.
- Achieved back to back conference championships (NEC) and making an NCAA appearance in the 2018 & 2019 seasons.

Colonial Leadership Academy

Moon Township, PA | Oct. 2017-2018

- Participated in interactive sessions designed to enhance leadership skills and listened to guest speakers discuss insights into leadership.
- Studied and applied lessons from the book *Developing the Leader Within You* (John C. Maxwell) towards daily life on and off the field.

Selection Committee to Hire New RMU Athletic Director

Moon Township, PA | April 2019

- Selected as an exceptional student-athlete to be on the committee
- Prepared questions, and interviewed candidates for new role

Mooncrest Volunteer Program

Moon Township, PA | Oct.2017-Present

- Serve as a role model to underprivileged children.
- Tutor and provide support with school work and their arts and crafts.
- Assist in setup and cleanup pf holiday parties (Halloween and Christmas).

RMU Lead Program

Moon Township, PA | Aug. 2016

- Attended seminars about leadership with guest speakers.
- · Preformed different teambuilding activities.
- Participated in different service events within the local area.